Brian Barrow - Developer Experience Engineer

(801) 651-4206

https://briancbarrow.com/

briancbarrow@gmail.com

I am a full stack web developer with experience in modern technologies. I like being part of a team where I can see my individual contributions reach a common goal. I like helping the community and enjoy taking the lead on community driven events/projects. I am currently an organizer for the UtahJS conference for the past 4 years, and for the last 6.5 years I have been running a study group in the Salt Lake City area for people learning to code

I love being able to create things using code and find it very rewarding. I am passionate about mentoring and helping others grow.

KEY COMPETENCIES

Software Development

Skills include JavaScript, Vue, React, Astro, Node, Deno and some AWS/cloud experience. I also recently started learning Go in order to develop the Go SDK for the Deepgram API, and have started diving deeper into Python and Go with a friend from my study group.

Mentorship

My favorite accomplishments have been centered around the work I've done in communities. In both organizing events and speaking at conferences.

EXPERIENCE

Developer Experience Engineer - Deepgram

Sept 2021 - Present

- Built two iterations of the Deepgram API documentation with Vue.js/Nuxt and also Astro/Storyblok
- Developed Deno and Go SDKs, and maintained Node, Python SDKs to aid developing with Deepgram API
- Wrote blog posts about Deepgram and other web technologies
- Built relationships with conference planners to use Deepgram's event captioner tool
- Delivered talks at UtahJS and Kansas City Developer Conference

Events Organizer - UtahJS

2016 - Present

- Organized a study group for people learning to code
- Mentored attendees and organized more veteran participants into co-hosting the event
- Coordinate annual UtahJS conference

Author- freeCodeCamp.org

July 2020 - Present

- Authored several articles for freeCodeCamp's blog
- https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/author/brian/

Frontend JavaScript Developer - Homie

July 2020 - Sept 2021

Developed micro front-end applications in Nuxt/Vue.js and Tailwind CSS

• Established and ran the apprenticeship program, bringing on and mentoring apprentices for the web team in order to train them and build a pipeline of talent with a 100% post-completion employment rate

Software Engineer - CHG Healthcare

April 2019 - July 2020

- Developed front-end portal application in Nuxt/Vue.js
- Developed back end in Node/Express with AWS Lambda
- Participated in scrum ceremonies

Developer - Signs.com

May 2017 - April 2019

- Refactored site to be responsive and mobile friendly
- Established best practices for CSS across repository

Workshop Instructor - Thinkful

August 2018 - January 2019

- Presented introductory web development workshops for people beginning to learn code
- Mentored students about learning paths in web development

Freelance, Salt Lake City UT - Web Developer

March 2017 - May 2017

- Freelance Web Development using React/Redux
- Built reusable components for client web applications

EDUCATION

Thinkful.com, Online - Full-Stack Development

Graduation: January 2017

BYU-Idaho Rexburg ID - BS Business Management Supply Chain Management

Graduation: July 2012

HOBBIES/INTERESTS

My main hobby is playing Disc Golf. It gives me time to spend outside and with friends. I even attended the Disc Golf World Championships in 2021 when they came to Utah. I love spending time with my family and am a coach for my sons' recreational basketball teams. I also love reading. I read mostly non-fiction, but enjoy reading some science-fiction and fantasy books to change things up.